Guide to the Cornwall Miscellanea 1779-2003 MS 011 MS 011 MS 011
Cornwall Historical Society
- Photographic Materials
  - Photographs
    - Topics
      - Schools
        - District 3 School, June 18, 1911-July 1917, N.D. (Box 28, Folder 8)
          Photographs from the third school district located in Cornwall Center. There are photos of the school house, as well as a barn owned by Charles Osborne that was supposedly built from materials taken from the school after it was torn down.
        - District 4 School, 1919, N.D. (Box 28, Folder 9)
          Photographs from the third school district, which was located in Johnson Hollow. There are photos of the school house, which was built in 1840 and torn down by the 1970s, as well as class photos.
        - District 5 School, 1917-January 1995 (Box 28, Folder 10)
          Photographs from the fifth school district, which was located in Cream Hill. The Queen Anne-style school house stood on Scoville Road and is currently a private residence. There are photos of the school house and of various students and teachers.
        - District 6 School, circa 1915-1933, N.D. (Box 28, Folder 11)
          Photographs from the sixth school district, which was located along Ford Road in Cornwall Hollow. There are photos of the school house as well as class pictures.
        - District 7 School, N.D. (Box 28, Folder 12)
          Photographs of the District 7 school house located along Route 128. It is currently a private residence.
        - District 8 School, N.D. (Box 28, Folder 13)
          Photographs of the interior and exterior of the District 8 school house, which was located in Cornwall Bridge.
        - District 10 School, 1914, N.D. (Box 28, Folder 14)
          Photographs of the District 10 school house, which stood near Dudleytown Road.
        - District 11 School, N.D. (Box 28, Folder 15)
          Photographs of the interior and exterior of the District 11 school house, which stood near West Cornwall.
        - District 12 School, 1932, N.D. (Box 28, Folder 16)
          Photographs from the twelfth school district, which was located in North Cornwall. In 1922, the building became the private residence of William Bierce. There are photos of the school house and of students.
        - District 14 School, 1989, N.D. (Box 28, Folder 17)
          Photographs of the District 14 school house along Great Hollow Road. Today, the building is a private residence.
        - District 15: Students and Teachers, circa 1910-1939, N.D. (Box 28, Folder 18)
          Photographs of students and teachers from the fifteenth school district in West Cornwall. Many of the photographs are class pictures.
        - District 15 School House, 1933-1989, N.D. (Box 28, Folder 19)
          Photographs of the District 15 school house on Lower River Road in West Cornwall. The building later served as the Hughes Memorial Library.
        - District 16 School, 1903-1933, N.D. (Box 28, Folder 20)
          Photographs from the sixteenth school district, which was located in East Cornwall. There are photos of the school house and of various students and teachers.
        - Cornwall Consolidated School: Mabel Engisch Album, 1954 (Box 28, Folder 21)
          Photo album presented to Mabel Engisch by her class.
        - District 17 School, circa 1911 (Box 29, Folder 1)
          Photograph of the District 17 school house, which was located near Flat Rocks Road.
        - West Cornwall Sunday School (Box 29, Folder 2)
          Photographs of students from the West Cornwall Sunday School.
        - Foreign Mission School, August 1947, N.D. (Box 29, Folder 3)
          Photographs related to the Foreign Mission School, which existed from 1817-1826 in Cornwall Plain. There are photos of the school house, as well as a picture of a monument dedicated to Henry Obukaha'ia in Hawaii, and a picture of a lantern that belonged to John Northrop, the steward of the school.
        - Miscellaneous Students, 1989, N.D. (Box 29, Folder 4)
          Photographs of unspecified students and teachers.
        - Rumsey Hall, 1987-1988 (Box 35, Folder 17)
          Photographs of the former Rumsey Hall school building, which the Town of Cornwall was considering buying and converting into town offices.
        - Cornwall Consolidated School, 1940-1988 (Box 35, Folder 18)
          Photographs of the Cornwall Consolidated School.
      - Events
        - Library Centennial, August 16, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 5)
          Photographs from the festivities surrounding the centennial of the Cornwall Library, including pageants and musical acts.
          - Library Centennial Pageant, August 16, 1969 (Box OS 3, Folder 12)
            Overside photographs from the centennial celebration at the Cornwall Library.
          - Library Centennial, August 16, 1969 (Box OS 3, Folder 23)
            Oversize photographs of the library centennial celebration.
        - Cornwall 250th Anniversary Parade, June 30, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 6)
          Color photographs of the parade held in comemmoration of Cornwall's 250th anniversary of incorporation.
        - Cornwall 250th Anniversary Parade, June 30, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 7)
          Black and white photographs of the celebration marking Cornwall's 250th anniversary of incorporation.
        - Memorial Day Commemorations, circa 1940-1961 (Box 29, Folder 8)
          Photgraphs of Memorial Day parades and speeches.
        - Memorial Day Celebrations, 1962-circa 1994 (Box 29, Folder 9)
          Photographs from Memorial Day parades and commemorations.
        - Memorial Day Commemorations, 1962-circa 1994 (Box 29, Folder 9)
          Photographs from Memorial Day parades and commemorations
        - Memorial Day, National Bicentennial, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 10)
          Photographs from Memorial Day celebrations that coincided with the nation's bicentennial. Photos include images of speaking engagements at the North Cornwall Meeting House and a concert on the Town Green.
        - Cornwall Bicentennial, August 19, 1939 (Box 29, Folder 11)
          Photographs of a speaking engagament from the old library in commemoration of the Cornwall Bicentennial.
        - Tornado Anniversary Party, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 12)
          Photographs from the party marking the one year anniversary of the 1989 Tornado. Photos include images of a watermelon eating contest and a parade.
        - Sheep Shearing, May 1972 (Box 29, Folder 13)
          Photographs of sheep spearing and wool spinning on the Cornwall Town Green.
        - Ice Cutting on the Housatonic River, N.D. (Box 29, Folder 14)
          Photographs of people cutting ice on the Housatonic River in an apparent modern recreation of historic ice cutting methods.
        - Cornwall Boy's Club Breakfast, N.D. (Box 29, Folder 15)
          Photographs of four unidentified members of the Cornwall Boys Club sitting for breakfast.
        - North Cornwall Congregation 250th Anniversary Album: Part I, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 16)
          The first nine pages of photographs from an album commemorating the 250th anniversary of the establishment of the North Cornwall Congregation.
        - North Cornwall Congregation 250th Anniversary Album: Part II, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 17)
          The final ten pages from the photo album commemorating the 250th anniversary of the North Cornwall Congregation. Items include photographs of an historical play put on by the church, as well as the play's program.
        - Pris Dickson Party, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 18)
          Photographs of a dinner party held by Pris Dickson.
        - Naneen and Sterling Bunnell Party, 1988 (Box 29, Folder 19)
          Photographs of a dinner party hosted by Naneen and Sterling Bunnell.
        - Dedication of Pioneer Monument, July 4, 1922 (Box 29, Folder 20)
          Photograph of W.B. Hubbard, Patrick O'Donnell, E.C. Starr, and L.J. Nickerson at the dedication of the Pioneer Monument in North Cornwall.
        - Down Home Celebrations, 1926, N.D. (Box 29, Folder 21)
          Photographs of Down Home Pageants held in North Cornwall.
        - Old Home Day, 1913 (Box 29, Folder 22)
          Photograph of a picnic held in North Cornwall on Old Home Day.
        - Hunting, circa 1901, N.D. (Box 29, Folder 23)
          Photographs of Cornwall hunting parties.
        - Election Days (Box 29, Folder 24)
          Photographs from an unspecified election taken in the Cornwall Town Offices.
        - Fennell Day, N.D. (Box 29, Folder 25)
          Photograph of the annual visit of Reverend Fennell to the East Cornwall Baptist Church.
        - Miscellaneous Church Events, 1944-1988, N.D. (Box 29, Folder 26)
          Photographs of assorted church events in Cornwall. Specific images include Easter Sunday 1944 and a speaking event at the North Cornwall Meeting House.
        - Picnics, June 1944, N.D. (Box 29, Folder 27)
          Photographs of assorted Cornwall picnickers.
        - Miscellaneous, 1909-2010, N.D. (Box 29, Folder 28)
          Photographs of miscellaneous events and gatherings in Cornwall. One labeled image portrays a gathering of Cornwall residents born in 1930 gathered at Mohawk Ski Area.
        - Rummage Sale, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 1)
          Photographs of shoppers at the annual Cornwall Rummage Sale.
        - Rummage Sale, N.D. (Box 30, Folder 2)
          Photographs of shoppers and items from an unspecified Rummage Sale.
        - Rummage Sale, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 3)
          Photographs of shoppers and items from the annual Cornwall Rummage Sale at the Parish House.
        - Rummage Sale Wares, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 4)
          Photographs of items for sale at the Cornwall Rummage Sale.
        - Memorial Day, 1992 (Box 30, Folder 5)
          Photographs of a speech given on Memorial Day.
        - Old Home Day, August 18, 1963 (Box 35, Folder 25)
          Images from Old Home Day taken in Cornwall Plain.
        - Agricultural Fair, 1983 (Box 36, Folder 7)
          Photograph of sheep at the Agricultural Fair.
        - Agricultural Fair, August 1995 (Box 36, Folder 8)
          Photographs of the Cornwall Agricultural Fair.
        - Agricultural Fair, September 1996 (Box 36, Folder 9)
          Photographs of the attendees and events at the Cornwall Agricultural Fair.
        - Agricultural Fair: Part I, October 1999 (Box 36, Folder 10)
          Photographs of the Cornwall Agricultural Fair taken by Pat and Jerry Blakey.
        - Cornwall Agricultural Fair: Part II, October 1999 (Box 36, Folder 11)
          Photographs of the Cornwall Agricultural Fair taken by an anonymous attendee.
        - Agricultural Fair: Part III, October 1999 (Box 36, Folder 12)
          Photographs of events and demonstrations at the Cornwall Agricultural Fair taken by an anonymous attendee.
        - Agricultural Fair, September 2006 (Box 36, Folder 13)
          Photographs of the Cornwall Historical Society booth at the Agricultural Fair.
        - Agricultural Fair: Participating Farms, N.D. (Box 36, Folder 14)
          Photographs of the Russ, Ridgeway, Lorch, Benjamin, Hedden, Scoville and Cream Hill farms.
        - Cornwall Cup, July 1995 (Box 36, Folder 15)
          Photographs of the West Cornwall, Cornwall Bridge, and Cornwall Village baseball teams.
        - Cornwall Cup, July 1996 (Box 36, Folder 16)
          Photographs of the Cornwall Cup baseball game.
      - Cornwall Historical Society
        - Veterans Exhibit: World War I Photographs, 1917-1918 (Box 30, Folder 6)
          World War I photographs used by the Cornwall Historical Society for its exhibition on veterans. There are photos of Cornwall men in the Home Guard, unidentified soldiers in camp, the USS Bridgeport, Red Cross nurses, and specific soldiers from Cornwall. Soldiers include John Marsh, Whittlesey Hart, and Harry Breen.
        - Veterans Exhibit: World War I Posters Part I, N.D. (Box 30, Folder 7)
          Photographs of World War I posters used by the Cornwall Historical Society for the exhibit on veterans.
        - Veterans Exhibit: World War I Posters Part II, N.D. (Box 30, Folder 8)
        - Veterans Exhibit: World War I Posters Part III, N.D. (Box 30, Folder 9)
          Photographs of World War I posters used in the Cornwall Historical Society exhibit on veterans.
        - Veterans Exhibit: World War II Bombers, N.D. (Box 30, Folder 10)
          Copies of two photographs of American bombers from Charles Hepprick.
        - Veterans Exhibit: Observation Post Bravo Metro, N.D. (Box 30, Folder 11)
          Photographs of Walt Preston, Jack Preston, Bessie Blake, Ann Barns Landeck, and Rachel Speiden Breck at Observation Post Bravo Metro.
        - Veterans Exhibit: Korean War, N.D. (Box 30, Folder 12)
          Copies of Korean War photographs belonging to D. Pelliter used in the Veterans Exhibit.
        - Out of the Woods Exhibit, August 30, 2011 (Box 30, Folder 13)
          Photographs of stump props from the Out of the Woods Exhibit.
        - Dr. Walker Exhibit, June 24, 2011, N.D. (Box 30, Folder 14)
          Photographs from the Dr. Brad Walker Exhibit. Photos include images of Dr. Walker and of the sign from his practice.
        - Foreign Mission School, N.D. (Box 30, Folder 15)
          Photographs from the exhibit on the Foreign Mission School. Photos include copies of images from the Chinese Friendship Album as well as pictures of the exhibit itself.
        - Millinery Exhibit, February 1983 (Box 30, Folder 16)
          Photographs of mannequins and hats used in the Millinery Exhibit.
        - Silver Teapot Exhibit, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 17)
          Photographs of early American silver teapot.
        - Veterans Exhibit: Memorial Items, N.D. (Box 30, Folder 18)
          Photographs of veterans' names from war memorials on the Town Green. Also, an image of the ship that Frank Trager served on during World War II, the USS Endicott.
        - Lydia Maria Brewster Hubbard Exhibit, 2004 (Box 30, Folder 19)
          Photographs of artwork by Lydia Maria Brewster Hubbard.
        - Ruth Gannett Exhibit, 1997 (Box 30, Folder 20)
          Photographs of artwork by Ruth Gannett.
        - Ben Foster Exhibit, 1982 (Box 30, Folder 21)
          Photographs of artwork by Ben Foster.
        - Ben Foster Exhibit, 2002 (Box 30, Folder 22)
        - Agricultural Fair Exhibit, N.D. (Box 30, Folder 23)
          Photographs used for the Agricultural Fair Exhibit. There are pictures from the Ives Farm as well as of various types of cattle.
        - Miscellaneous, N.D. (Box 30, Folder 24)
          Photographs of Main Street in Cornwall Plain, the C.E. Wilcox & Sons store on the Green, and a group of people at Cream Hill Lake.
        - Then and Now Exhibit (Box 30, Folder 25)
          Photographs from the Then and Now Exhibit. Photos include copies of historic pictures taken in West Cornwall.
        - Veterans Exhibit: Cornwall Veterans, 1941-1968, N.D. (Box 30, Folder 26)
          Photographs of Cornwall veterans. Specific service people include James J. Blakey, Col. Cooke, Donald B. Polk, Doris Locke, and Elizabeth Locke.
        - Then and Now Exhibit (Box 31, Folder 1)
          Historic photographs of West Cornwall used in the Then and Now Exhibit.
        - Then and Now Exhibit (Box 31, Folder 2)
        - Map Exhibit, N.D. (Box 31, Folder 3)
          Photographs of maps from the Map Exhibit.
        - Visionary Maps of Cornwall, N.D. (Box 31, Folder 4)
          Photographs of maps created for the Cornwall Map Project.
        - Visionary Maps of Cornwall: Part II, N.D. (Box 31, Folder 5)
          Second part of the collection of photographs from the Cornwall Map Project.
        - What Did We Do Before TV? Exhibit, N.D. (Box 31, Folder 6)
          Photographs used in the What Did We Do Before TV? Exhibit. Specific images include a team of horses plowing snow and Mr. and Mrs. Rogers playing cards.
        - Ice Cream Social, N.D. (Box 31, Folder 7)
          Photographs of an ice cream social held at the Cornwall Historical Society.
        - Mannequins, February 2006 (Box 31, Folder 8)
          Photographs of mannequins set up at the Cornwall Historical Society.
        - Building Maintenance, June 25, 1999-June 2004, N.D. (Box 31, Folder 9)
          Photographs of various maintenance and repair projects at the Cornwall Historical Society.
        - School Programs, October 14, 2005, N.D. (Box 31, Folder 10)
          Photographs of a visit to the historical society by a group of fourth graders and of the chalk board from the District 15 School.
        - Oral History Talks, 2001-2002 (Box 31, Folder 11)
          Photographs from oral history talks held in Cornwall.
        - Miscellaneous Artwork From Past Exhibits, N.D. (Box 31, Folder 12)
          Photographs of assorted artwork used in various historical society exhibits.
        - Then and Now Exhibit: Cover Photo (Box 35, Folder 1)
          Cover photograph from an album of the sites covered by the Then and Now Exhibit. Photograph by Cara Weigold.
        - Then and Now Exhibit: Cornwall Bridge (Box 35, Folder 2)
          Then and Now photographs of 95 Kent Road South and 156 Kent Road South.
        - Then and Now Exhibit: Cornwall Hollow (Box 35, Folder 3)
          Then and Now photographs of 35 Fox Road, 400 Cornwall Hollow Road, 128 Cornwall Hollow Road, 146 Cornwall Hollow Road, 78 Johnson Road, 30 Bradford Road, and 6 Rexford Road.
        - Then and Now Exhibit: Cornwall Plain (Box 35, Folder 4)
          Then and Now photographs of 14 Bolton Hill Road, the Berkshire Country Store, 57 Todd Hill Road, 39 Jewell Street, 48 Jewell Street, 15 Pine Street, 9 Pine Street, and 1 Pine Street.
        - Then and Now Exhibit: Cream Hill (Box 35, Folder 5)
          Then and Now photographs of 67 Scoville Road, 256 Town Street, 143 Cream Hill Road, 157 Cream Hill Road, 199 Cream Hill Road, and 344 Cream Hill Road.
        - Then and Now Exhibit: East Cornwall (Box 35, Folder 6)
          Then and Now photographs of 133 Great Hollow Road, 174 Great Hill Road, and 196 Great Hill Road.
        - Then and Now Exhibit: North Cornwall (Box 35, Folder 7)
          Then and Now photographs of 7 Town Street, 91 Town Street, 137 Town Street, 83 Coggswell Road, and 106 Coggswell Road.
        - Then and Now Exhibit: Sharon-Goshen Turnpike (Box 35, Folder 8)
          Then and Now photographs of 350 Sharon-Goshen Turnpike, 169 Sharon-Goshen Turnpike, and 82 Sharon-Goshen Turnpike.
        - Then and Now Exhibit: West Cornwall (Box 35, Folder 9)
          Then and Now photogrpahs of 9 River Road, 14 River Road, 40 Lower River Road, the Toll House, the Covered Bridge, the Wandering Moose Cafe, Cornwall Bridge Pottery, 15 River Road, Cochrane Bros. general store, the post office, 14 Lower River Road, 38 Lower River Road, the Hughes Memorial Library, and 18 River Road.
        - Cornwall In Pictures: Planning Phase, 2001 (Box 35, Folder 37)
          Photographs from the planning phase of the book, Cornwall In Pictures.
        - Cornwall In Pictures: Planning Phase Part II, 2001 (Box 35, Folder 38)
          Photographs from the planning phase of the publication, Cornwall In Pictures.
        - Cornwall In Pictures: Map Research, 2001 (Box 35, Folder 39)
          Photographs of map research being done for Cornwall In Pictures.
        - Cornwall In Pictures: Arrival from Publishers, 2002 (Box 35, Folder 40)
          Photographs of the arrrival of copies of Cornwall In Pictures.
        - Cornwall In Pictures, 2002 (Box 35, Folder 41)
          Photographs of the editorial board inspecting the finalized copy of Cornwall In Pictures.
        - Cornwall In Pictures: Recording Studio, 2002 (Box 35, Folder 42)
          Photographs of the editorial board in a recording studio following the publication of the book.
        - Cornwall In Pictures: Miscellaneous, 2001-2002 (Box 35, Folder 43)
          Miscellaneous photographs from the publication process of Cornwall In Pictures.
      - Sedgwick-Related Photographs
        - Personal photographs owned by Gen. John Sedgwick, June 18, 1863, N.D. (Box 31, Folder 13)
          Personal photographs owned by John Sedgwick. Items include a portrait of himself, as well as photos of L. Hunt and M.G. Jones.
        - Sedgwick and Staff (Box 31, Folder 14)
          Photographs of John Sedgwick with his staff of officers.
        - Portraits, N.D. (Box 31, Folder 15)
          Portraits of Gen. John Sedgwick.
        - Sedgwick House, 1900-1992, N.D. (Box 31, Folder 16)
          Photographs of the Gen. John Sedgwick House in Cornwall Hollow.
        - Monument Dedication: Part I, 1900 (Box 31, Folder 17)
          Photographs from the dedication of the Sedgwick Monument in Cornwall Hollow.
        - Monument Dedication: Part II, 1900 (Box 31, Folder 18)
        - Sedgwick Grave Decoration, May 30, 1900 (Box 31, Folder 19)
          Photographs from the decoration of Gen. Sedgwick's grave on Decoration Day 1900.
        - 100th Anniversary of Sedgwick's Death, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 20)
          Photographs of the ceremony at the Sedgwick Monument commemorating the 100th anniversary of Sedgwick's death.
        - Miscellaneous Monument Photographs, circa 1930-1941, N.D. (Box 31, Folder 21)
          Assorted photographs of the Sedgwick Monument in Cornwall Hollow.
        - Reenactors at Sedgwick Monument, 1989 (Box 31, Folder 22)
          Photographs of Civil War reenactors at the Sedgwick Monument in Cornwall Hollow.
        - Fort Sedgwick, September 1864, N.D. (Box 32, Folder 1)
          Photographs of Fort Sedgwick, an earthenworks fortification that was built near Petersburg, Virginia.
        - Bust, N.D. (Box 32, Folder 2)
          Photograph of a bust of Gen. John Sedgwick.
        - Sedgwick's Sword, N.D. (Box 32, Folder 3)
          Photograph of Sedgwick's sword. Photo one of a series donated by Mrs. John C. Kendall of Norfolk, Conn.
        - Cemetery Hill at Gettysburg, N.D. (Box 32, Folder 4)
          Photograph of Cemetery Hill at Gettysburg.
        - Sedgwick Monument Restoration, June 1992, N.D. (Box 32, Folder 5)
          Photographs of the restoration work done on the Sedgwick Monument in Cornwall Hollow.
        - Sedgwick Monument Rededication, 1994 (Box 32, Folder 6)
          Photographs from the rededication of the Sedgwick Monument in Cornwall Hollow.
        - Monument Dedication, May 30, 1900 (Box OS 2, Folder 1)
          Photograph of Connecticut Governor Lounsbury speaking at the dedication of the Sedgwick Monument in Cornwall Hollow. Photo taken by Mrs. John C. Kendall of Norfolk, Conn.
        - Monument Dedication, May 30, 1900 (Box OS 2, Folder 2)
          Another photograph of Governor Lounsbury speaking at the dedication of the Sedgwick Monument in Cornwall Hollow.
        - T.S. Gold Memorial Address, N.D. (Box OS 2, Folder 3)
          Photograph of T.S. Gold speaking at the Sedgwick Monument in Cornwall Hollow.
        - Monument Dedication, May 30, 1900 (Box OS 2, Folder 4)
          Photograph of the Sedgwick Monument prior to its formal dedication.
        - Monument Dedication, May 30, 1900 (Box OS 2, Folder 5)
          Photograph of the unveiling of the Sedgwick Monument in Cornwall Hollow taken by Mrs. John C. Kendall.
        - Grave Decoration, May 30, 1900 (Box OS 2, Folder 6)
          Photograph of the decorated grave of Gen. John Sedgwick in Cornwall Hollow.
        - Cemetery, May 30, 1900 (Box OS 2, Folder 7)
          Photograph of a crowd gathered around the grave of Gen. John Sedgwick.
        - Graveside Prayer, May 30, 1900 (Box OS 2, Folder 8)
          Photograph of men praying at the grave of Gen. John Sedgwick.
        - Sedgwick House, N.D. (Box OS 2, Folder 9)
          Photograph of the Gen. John Sedgwick House taken by Mrs. John C. Kendall.
        - Decoration Ceremony, 1900 (Box OS 2, Folder 10)